Matthew Judd

Web content and project management

11 Marshall Street Newtown, 3220 0466 805 442 matt@juddcentral.net

Folio: mattjudd.github.io/folio/

An experienced digital content manager with a core background of publishing and web development - a career history that extends to web, print, and TV at leading companies in London, Melbourne, and Wellington.

At home with both online and print publishing, having produced high-quality content in fast-paced, deadline-driven environments.

Flagship work includes:

- end-to-end digital campaign management: client, stakeholder, and schedule management; campaign web content, EDMs, and analytics;
- producing AWS server-based HTML/CSS/JS/PHP templates for generating personalised data-responsive videos;
- website content management and development;
- designing/producing a scheduling management tool for TheLancet.com;
- repurposing content into eBook packages for Amazon, iBooks, and Kobo;
- migrating the archive of Lancet online content into a new global CMS.

Recognised among colleagues for: paying attention to the details, "owning" my work, clear communication, and "getting it done".

Skills

An experienced digital content manager, I have worked within many large-scale CMS infrastructures, each custom-built for the company concerned.

I am proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript libraries, and PHP. I currently work with VueJS infrastructure, can manage Git repositories, AWS services, and databases. I have worked with and helped integrate API arrangements.

An Adobe CS, Google, and Microsoft Office professional, I am very capable with all admin and content management software. Platforms like Google Analytics and Microsoft Sharepoint would usually go without saying.

Project management: practising Agile, and trained in PRINCE-2. I have used Jira, Monday.com, Accelo, Trello, Slack, and BitBucket. My current favourite is Asana.

Experience

Visual Domain - Web campaign manager, developer, team leader SEPT 2015 - PRESENT, MELBOURNE

As campaign manager, I personally handle end-to-end management of all Visual Domain's personalised video campaigns: bringing together stakeholders, front-end deliverables, back-end infrastructure, analytics, and client expectations.

As the lead developer for the personalised video products, I have a key roles in creative pitches, client consultations, and tender processes. I am responsible for preparation of the data-responsive video templates and interactive videos, using HTML, CSS, JavaScript libraries (including VueJS), PHP. I

Additional notes

- Content management: Designing, UX, and building responsive web campaign landing pages and online forms/dashboards;
- Laravel PHP platform infrastructure
- Managing Amazon Web Services (AWS) EC2, S3, Cloudwatch and SQS;
- Git repository management;
- Building and managing EDM templates and campaigns;

TheLancet.com @ **Elsevier Ltd** - Digital content and project manager, Global E-Operations department

JAN 2014 - JULY 2015, LONDON, UK

Digital content management, development and campaigns on TheLancet.com, driving content through Elsevier's global CMS.

Working with 80+ internal and external stakeholders (editorial, production, marketing, technical, international), providing support, and resolving issues.

The Lancet.com presents original academic research across many independent *Lancet* journals, hundreds of themed medical research series and editorial campaigns, while interlinking content with complementary multimedia. A world-leading medical research publisher, *The Lancet*'s content is deadline-driven, frequently time-sensitive, and follows strict international embargo rules.

Projects

- Scheduling database: proposed, designed, produced. A web-based database with secure login, global access, data submission management, reporting features. An agile project.
- Integration and redesign of established workflows (internal and external) into Elsevier's Production Tracking System (PTS). Significant compatibility issues, cross-department stakeholders.

Additional roles

- Local Application Manager: Designated Lancet expert on PTS and associated databases. A company role, part of an international collective of LAMs that meet regularly, occasionally in Amsterdam.
- **Staff management**: supervision, training, workload allocation, support of contract staff.
- Lancet staff representative: on the Elsevier UK Staff Council (3+ years)

Regular responsibilities

- Multi-platform content management for web, primarily via Literatum a customised global CMS.
- Scheduling, quality control, and communication across editorial, marketing, PR, and production departments.
- Suppliers: close relationship with external suppliers in Chennai, India, and California, USA.
- International stakeholders: regular logistics collaboration with Elsevier colleagues in Amsterdam, St Louis, New York, Oxford.
- Creative design as the occasion demands it: eg, a social-media-friendly infographic hub.
- Cross-browser and device testing; A/B testing.
- Supporting the Marketing team's EDM campaigns

The Lancet journals @ Elsevier Ltd - Senior Production Editor, eBook producer

OCT 2010 - DEC 2013, LONDON, UK

Seven independent Lancet titles, primarily responsible for the weekly flagship journal: *The Lancet*. Working in a networked Adobe Creative Suite production environment, I managed content and produced page composition to daily, weekly, and monthly deadlines for web and print delivery.

- Designed, produced, and published The Lancet's first eBook titles: released on Amazon's (Kindle) and Apple's (iBooks) global stores, leading to 15000+ downloads worldwide in first 9 months
- Administrator, Lancet Global Health blog page
- Participating in UAT for The Lancet iPad app

SAGE Publications - Production Editor

APRIL 2008 - OCT 2010, LONDON, UK

Coordinating production of internationally distributed engineering journals, from editorial acceptance through to publication online and in print.

VisitBritain Publishing - Media administration

2007 - 2008, LONDON, UK

A 'jack-of-all-trades' in media administration: managing CMS, contributing to PR, research, XML/HTML editing, distribution, eCommerce databases, and marketing of 15 VisitBritain titles and three VisitBritain websites.

New Media Age, Centaur Communications - Researcher

2007. LONDON, UK

New Media Age was a weekly B2B publication, releasing highly regarded annual Top 100 Guide to Interactive Agencies. I collated information on 250+ UK-based new media agencies, leading to researching, writing and/or editing 100+ profiles.

Education

RMIT - BA (Media) — media production and literature

1999 - 2004, CITY CAMPUS, MELBOURNE

Awards

(2010) Young Publisher Grant recipient from the Society for Scholarly Publishing to attend their annual conference in San Francisco, June 2010.

(2002) Tony Staley Award for best Australian community program (2002). Assistant Producer/Editor/Floor Manager, Dawn's Crack, Saturday morning variety TV, Channel 31, Melbourne.